<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-13T07:15:46+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Ambivert</title><subtitle>'Me, Myself Bibek Chalise.'</subtitle><author><name>Bibek Chalise</name></author><entry><title type="html">A Journey Part (i)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/technology,/acheivement,/msp/2020/02/12/A-Journey-part-(I)/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Journey Part (i)" /><published>2020-02-12T08:03:27+05:45</published><updated>2020-02-12T08:03:27+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/technology,/acheivement,/msp/2020/02/12/A-Journey-part-(I)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/technology,/acheivement,/msp/2020/02/12/A-Journey-part-(I)/">&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: “So Much So……”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Feb 12, 2020, I feel like I did something that I hadn’t done before. I gave a presentation to around 50 people with full confidence, no shivering legs, no broken mind, no sweety palm, no fumbling of words and no dry lips (Sorry, I am joking for this one). From the first slide, I felt like my lips were getting as dry as I am in the center of Sahara Desert (Shit! Bad phrase).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was prepared with the slide a week ago, I pulled, pushed the ideas and slides from the community that I was engaged on and then merged all of it. I had that idea running in my mind, I will deliver the best presentation that everyone in the room has been seen. But, 29 freaking slides. &lt;strong&gt;What?&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, a freaking number of slides, guess how bored anyone will be in the room will be watching me trying to explain 29 slides with each point on it. The first rule of the presentation I learned at the end of the day, &lt;strong&gt;“Keep Slides the less as you can”&lt;/strong&gt;. Next time, things will turn round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second law of presentation that I violated, &lt;strong&gt;“Keep memes in-between”. Fuck hell!&lt;/strong&gt; I didn’t do it. How the hell in the world, I can miss it. Next time, a to-do list when having a presentation, &lt;strong&gt;Memes mandatory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough jokes for the day. Let’s dive into the serious talk. My journey of being a Speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Dashain, I applied for Microsoft Student Partner, which I wanted to be for a long time ago. I also tried for GitHub Campus expert but couldn’t be for various reasons. So, there was no sure chance of me getting an opportunity to be MSP. But last January, I got the confirmation mail from Microsoft. And I became an MSP. The biggest student partnership program in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then follow a mandatory post on Facebook. &lt;strong&gt;“Started job at Microsoft”&lt;/strong&gt;. I sometimes wonder how stimulation works on our mind, (The topic let be assumed on the next blog).  Congratulation received friends and family. A proud moment anyone can have as a student, to get a partnership from Microsoft. The learning path, promotion to second stage of the program and trying hard to achieve on the third level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the big day. To give presentation for everyone who wishes to be MSP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(That will follow on the next blog Part II of this series.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bibek Chalise</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="MSP" /><category term="Microsoft" /><category term="Acheivement" /><category term="Persoanl blog" /><summary type="html">Spoiler alert: “So Much So……”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Live life!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poetry/2020/02/04/live-life!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Live life!" /><published>2020-02-04T11:35:27+05:45</published><updated>2020-02-04T11:35:27+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poetry/2020/02/04/live-life!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poetry/2020/02/04/live-life!/">&lt;p&gt;Why take so much pressure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you can do so much the next day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun will shine for a reason&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What must wake up is you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment is now, the moment to live&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why worry when you are the one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is enough time per second&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What must rise is the will in you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take nothing for granted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why take a risk when unnecessary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is life occupied in you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What must be broken is the walls!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is for the winners&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why lose the game when you can win&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, losers has the greatest spirit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What must be taken is the teachings!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bibek Chalise</name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">Why take so much pressure?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Government Of Nepal Should Invest More On Iot?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/technology/2020/01/31/why-government-of-Nepal-should-invest-more-on-IoT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Government Of Nepal Should Invest More On Iot?" /><published>2020-01-31T08:03:27+05:45</published><updated>2020-01-31T08:03:27+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/technology/2020/01/31/why-government-of-Nepal-should-invest-more-on-IoT</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/technology/2020/01/31/why-government-of-Nepal-should-invest-more-on-IoT/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitalization of the world has already almost reached its zenith and with evolving technologies like Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Blockchain, Automated Technology, Augmented Reality, Digital Twin,  5G Network, and IoT, the template of human civilization is at its peak. If only we could put our mind into something extraordinary and then boom, technology comes into play, ideas are executed and things can happen.
Even though there`s a worldwide impact of such technologies, Nepal has still been very behind to use them for betterment. We have always relied on traditional technological tools which haven’t been productive for us. Nepal hasn’t yet invested in a prime technology which as a result has made us unable to utilize our own potential. So, it’s already time for us to take some bold moves and cultivate an environment for cutting edge technology. The Internet of Things could be the ideal one with which we can boost our way ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet of Things:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia defines The Internet of things (IoT) as the extension of internet connectivity into physical devices and everyday objects. IoT enables devices to interact with the internet embedded with electronics and sensors which can be controlled and monitored remotely. On a large scale, it covers other fields like AI, embedded systems and automation. It embraces traditional technologies to advanced form. This technology came to highlight a decade ago and is one of the technological trends of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet of Things and Nepal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, IoT could be the ideal technological investment for a country like Nepal. Progressively, things are changing. The world is taking benefit from IoT, so it’s high time to take action. Some of the ways the Nepal Government can take benefit from IoT are mentioned below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our aims is to create smart homes, smart cities, smart nation, smart cards, and ultimately smart citizens. For the very purpose, we must do some out of the box thinking and executions. The cities must be equipped with IoT controlled Traffic lights, smart parking areas, WiFi access areas, and properly planned transportation facilities. The real data manipulation and analysis will be the heart of such smart hubs. In such a scenario without the use of IoT powered technology, these concepts will only remain as words, nothing much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a well-known fact, every year Nepal faces huge losses due to calamities like floods, landslides and many more. The shattering earthquake is still on our minds. Different Countries have proven to out predict them meaning its already known if the calamities will strike or not but not us, we haven’t been able to do so. It all comes down to the use of mind and tech. If we can install IoT based sensors in dams and riversides, have IoT based, sensors that can analyze the water level and speed in real-time, sensors that can calculate the speed of wind-blowing and monitor rainfall over the certain range with GIS and satellite communication could be handy in the prediction of such natural catastrophes. The following awareness about the upcoming event of disasters could save hundreds of lives and millions of wealth. Not only this, the real-time communication is what IoT potent to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nepal is an agrarian country and agriculture is the sole of the income of our country. But we are facing the same problem in this sector too. We are using old-traditional tools and mechanisms in agriculture. In Agriculture, we can also Integrate IoT. If we use the Internet of Things, we can obtain real-time data of conditions like humanity, air, soil and condition fo crops. The health condition of animals can be obtained and it can be improved with the use of technology.  Similarly, with the smart irrigation concept, the dependency of monsoon can be ended as technology can self-measure the requirements of crops with time resulting in high productivity with less functional costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The travel and tourism industry can have a high prospect if there is a proper use of IoT based technologies. The IoT based technology can help the tourists to personalize their needs which ultimately makes the greater customer experience. Not only this they can have seamless transportation controlled by their own mobile device when the connectivity is maximized. They can travel with ease with proper location information, enjoy tourism-related sports and even get rescued in case of need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above matters, IoT will create an environment for new investment in the country that will unlock our potential to interact with third countries of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data collected in real-time will be beneficial and act as a data set for future references. The data so collected when used in ML and AI-based algorithms will make a significant result. Such results could be helpful in the planning of developmental projects. IoT is future technology and the Nepal government must invest in it for the sake of competing with other countries. Long in the future, wars and competitions will be backed by cyber-weapons, and IoT is one of them for developing countries like Nepal, which can serve on high note only if we invested some time and manpower in it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bibek Chalise</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Content Writing" /><summary type="html">Overview:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When the light’s bit shady.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fiction/2020/01/30/when-the-light's-bit-shady/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When the light’s bit shady." /><published>2020-01-30T11:35:27+05:45</published><updated>2020-01-30T11:35:27+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2020/01/30/when-the-light's-bit-shady</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fiction/2020/01/30/when-the-light's-bit-shady/">&lt;p&gt;When the light’s bit shady&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thirst in you dwells my land&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My land is a slum of unprotected souls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where your traces, protected with rubber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mastered to lure your hunger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You mastered to bargain mine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irony, it gets a different name&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You head up and I lost in day life-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small me, hoped for an arm to rest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every arm I now rest, sprinkle my chest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotten I ate were enough to live,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh I now eat tears me down to hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a hope abides on a full moon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light full of satisfaction asides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canopies build stoned with affection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which darkness pours the art, I reside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world rounds, the stars twinkle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So will the glooming moon shines,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me sleeping with a smile underneath it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A craft that no one can take away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bibek Chalise</name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">When the light’s bit shady</summary></entry></feed>